A Guide to the John H. Knowles Papers FA047
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Interim, 1971-1972; 3; 1 Cubic Feet
  This series contains correspondence relating to Knowles's appointment as president of The Rockefeller Foundation, covering the time between his resignation from Massachusetts General Hospital (December 1971) and the time he officially assumed presidency of the Foundation (July 1972). Included are letters from the Foundation's outgoing president George Harrar, congratulatory letters, and professional and personal correspondence.
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  - Appointment as President of The Rockefeller Foundation, March-June 1972 (Box 70, Folder 844)
  - Appointment as President of The Rockefeller Foundation, March-June 1972 (Box 70, Folder 845)
  - Appointment as President of The Rockefeller Foundation, March-June 1972 (Box 70, Folder 846)
  - Appointment as President of The Rockefeller Foundation, March-June 1972 (Box 70, Folder 847)
  - Appointment as President of The Rockefeller Foundation, November 1971-February 1972 (Box 71, Folder 848)
  - Appointment as President of The Rockefeller Foundation, November 1971-February 1972 (Box 71, Folder 849)
  - Appointment as President of The Rockefeller Foundation, November 1971-February 1972 (Box 71, Folder 850)
  - Appointment as President of The Rockefeller Foundation, November 1971-February 1972 (Box 71, Folder 851)
  - Appointment as President of The Rockefeller Foundation, November 1971-February 1972 (Box 71, Folder 852)
  - Appointment as President of The Rockefeller Foundation, November 1971-February 1972 (Box 71, Folder 853)
  - Appointment as President of The Rockefeller Foundation, August-October 1971 (Box 72, Folder 854)
  - Appointment as President of The Rockefeller Foundation, August-October 1971 (Box 72, Folder 855)
- The Rockefeller Foundation, 1961-1980; 4; 10 Cubic Feet
  This series consists of papers documenting Knowles's activities while president of The Rockefeller Foundation.
  Subseries A - Rockefeller Foundation
  - The Rockefeller Foundation, A
    Subseries A consists of correspondence, reports, and clippings relating to Knowles's work as president of The Rockefeller Foundation. Subjects include itineraries; trips to Cali, Colombia, St. Lucia, and Africa; trustee meetings; testimony before the House Subcommittee on Health and the Environment; and speeches by John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by subject and chronologically within each subject.
    - A (Box 72, Folder 856)
    - Activity Reports, 1972-1979 (Box 72, Folder 857)
    - African Trip, 1974-1975 (Box 72, Folder 858)
    - Appointment Congratulations, September 21, 1971-January 1972 (Box 72, Folder 859)
    - Appointment Congratulations, September 21, 1971-January 1972 (Box 72, Folder 860)
    - Appointment Congratulations, September 13-20, 1971 (Box 73, Folder 861)
    - Appointment Congratulations, September 13-20, 1971 (Box 73, Folder 862)
    - Arden House Foundation Meeting, 1972 (Box 73, Folder 863)
    - Articles about the Foundation, 1964, 1971 (Box 73, Folder 864)
    - Association of American Medical Colleges, 1974-1975 (Box 73, Folder 865)
    - B (Box 73, Folder 866)
    - Bicentennial, 1973 (Box 73, Folder 867)
    - C (Box 73, Folder 868)
    - Cali Trip, 1975 (Box 73, Folder 869)
    - Clippings - General, 1973-1978 (Box 73, Folder 870)
    - Clippings - Health, 1971, 1974-1977 (Box 73, Folder 871)
    - Clippings - Political Publicity, 1976 (Box 73, Folder 872)
    - Clippings, 1978 (Box 73A, Folder 872A)
    - Clippings, 1978 (Box 73A, Folder 872A)
    - Clippings - Rockefeller Foundation, 1976-1977 (Box 74, Folder 873)
    - Committee on Critical Choices for America, 1975 (Box 74, Folder 874)
    - Conferences, 1976-1977 (Box 74, Folder 875)
    - Council on Foundations, Inc., 1974-1975 (Box 74, Folder 876)
    - "The Course Ahead - The Rockefeller Foundation in the Next Five Years", 1974 (Box 74, Folder 877)
    - D (Box 74, Folder 878)
    - Domestic Health Policy Group, 1974-1975 (Box 74, Folder 879)
    - Domestic Health Policy Group, 1974-1975 (Box 74, Folder 880)
    - Education and Development (Box 74, Folder 881)
    - F (Box 75, Folder 882)
    - Fellowships for American Playwrights, 1972, 1976 (Box 75, Folder 883)
    - Federal University of Bahia, 1975 (Box 75, Folder 884)
    - The Future of Foundations (Box 75, Folder 885)
    - G (Box 75, Folder 886)
    - Hamden-Sydney College, 1973 (Box 75, Folder 887)
    - Harvard University - Department of Physics, 1971 (Box 75, Folder 888)
    - Health Education Foundation, 1976, 1978 (Box 75, Folder 889)
    - Hillcrest Conference, 1977 (Box 75, Folder 890)
    - Hospital Administration, 1973-1975 (Box 75, Folder 891)
    - Hurwitz, Raye, 1977 (Box 75, Folder 892)
    - Influenza Public Workshop - Bureau of Biologics - Food and Drug Administration, 1977 (Box 75, Folder 893)
    - Itineraries, 1972-1975 (Box 75, Folder 894)
    - Job Applications, 1974-1976 (Box 75, Folder 895)
    - Job Applications, 1974-1976 (Box 75, Folder 896)
    - Job Applications, 1974-1976 (Box 75, Folder 897)
    - Job Applications, 1972-1973 (Box 76, Folder 898)
    - Job Applications, 1972-1973 (Box 76, Folder 899)
    - Job Applications, 1972-1973 (Box 76, Folder 900)
    - Job Applications, 1972-1973 (Box 76, Folder 901)
    - Job Applications, 1972-1973 (Box 76, Folder 902)
    - K (Box 76, Folder 903)
    - Kennedy Center - Rockefeller Foundation International Competition, 1978 (Box 76, Folder 904)
    - L-M (Box 76, Folder 905)
    - N (Box 76, Folder 906)
    - National Center for a Voluntary Society, 1971-1973 (Box 77, Folder 907)
    - P (Box 77, Folder 908)
    - Phone Messages, 1972-1973, 1978-1979 (Box 77, Folder 909)
    - President's Report, 1974 (Box 77, Folder 910)
    - President's Report - Final Draft, 1974 (Box 77, Folder 911)
    - R (Box 77, Folder 912)
    - Recommendations, 1977-1978 (Box 77, Folder 913)
    - Recommendations - Candidates for College Presidency, 1973-1978 (Box 77, Folder 914)
    - Reference Service, 1972 (Box 78, Folder 915)
    - Rockefeller, John D., 3rd - Speeches, 1961, 1964-1965, 1967-1971 (Box 78, Folder 916)
    - Rockefeller, John D. 3rd - Speeches, 1961, 1964-1965, 1967-1971 (Box 78, Folder 917)
    - "RF Illustrated", 1974-1975 (Box 78, Folder 918)
    - "RF Staff and Program News", 1972 (Box 78, Folder 918A)
    - Rome Forum on the World Food Problem (Box 78, Folder 919)
    - S (Box 78, Folder 920)
    - St. Lucia Trip, 1973-1974 (Box 78, Folder 921)
    - Subcommittee on Health and the Environment - House Committee on Interstate and Foreign Commerce, 1976 (Box 78, Folder 922)
    - Travel Authorizations, 1972-1978 (Box 78, Folder 923)
    - Trustees, June 1973-1978 (Box 78, Folder 924)
    - Trustees, June 1973-1978 (Box 78, Folder 925)
    - Trustees, 1971-May 1973 (Box 79, Folder 926)
    - Trustees, 1971-May 1973 (Box 79, Folder 927)
    - Unidentified (Box 79, Folder 928)
    - United Nations Conference on Trade and Development, 1972 (Box 79, Folder 929)
    - Vitas (Box 79, Folder 930)
    - W (Box 79, Folder 931)
  - The Rockefeller Foundation - Professional, B
    Subseries B documents Knowles's professional interests and activities, mainly in the field of medicine. Subjects include the book "Doing Better and Feeling Worse," speaking engagements, the report "China Diary" of his 1975 trip to China, the Institute of Medicine, and an interview by the Kennedy Oral History Program.
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by subject and chronologically within each subject. There is also a correspondence file (1972-1975) arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
    - Abortion, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 932)
    - Advertising Council - Public Relations Committee, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 933)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1973-1974, 1978 (Box 79, Folder 934)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science - Scientific Freedom and Responsibility, 1971-1974 (Box 79, Folder 935)
    - American Clinical and Climatological Association, 1972-1975 (Box 79, Folder 936)
    - American National Red Cross (Box 79, Folder 937)
    - Associated Hospital Service of New York, 1972 (Box 80, Folder 938)
    - Belmont Hill School, 1972-1977 (Box 80, Folder 939)
    - Blue Cross/Blue Shield Symposium - The Future of Health in America, 1978 (Box 80, Folder 940)
    - Boston Library Society, 1972, 1975-1977 (Box 80, Folder 940A)
    - Boston University Board, 1974-1976 (Box 80, Folder 941)
    - Cambridge School, 1977 (Box 80, Folder 942)
    - "China Diary" - Correspondence, 1975-1977, 1979 (Box 80, Folder 943)
    - "China Diary" - Draft (Box 80, Folder 944)
    - "China Diary" - Draft (Box 80, Folder 945)
    - "China Diary" - Draft (Box 80, Folder 946)
    - Clippings, 1972-1978 (Box 80, Folder 947)
    - Costs, March 1972-June 1973 (Box 81, Folder 948)
    - Costs, March 1972-June 1973 (Box 81, Folder 949)
    - Council on Foreign Relations (Box 81, Folder 950)
    - Council on Foundations, 1972-1976 (Box 81, Folder 951)
    - "Doing Better and Feeling Worse" - Bill Anlyan, 1975-1976 (Box 81, Folder 952)
    - "Doing Better and Feeling Worse" - Ivan Bennett, 1976 (Box 81, Folder 953)
    - "Doing Better and Feeling Worse" - Daniel Callahan, 1976 (Box 81, Folder 954)
    - "Doing Better and Feeling Worse" - Merlin Duval, 1975-1976 (Box 81, Folder 955)
    - "Doing Better and Feeling Worse" - Bob Ebert, 1976-1977 (Box 81, Folder 956)
    - "Doing Better and Feeling Worse" - Leon Eisenberg, 1975-1976 (Box 81, Folder 957)
    - "Doing Better and Feeling Worse" - Renne C. Fox, 1975-1976 (Box 81, Folder 958)
    - "Doing Better and Feeling Worse" - Donald Frederickson, 1976 (Box 82, Folder 959)
    - "Doing Better and Feeling Worse" - Eli Ginzberg, 1975-1976 (Box 82, Folder 960)
    - "Doing Better and Feeling Worse" - David Hamberg, 1975-1976 (Box 82, Folder 961)
    - "Doing Better and Feeling Worse" - Herman Kahn, Jane Wewitt, 1975 (Box 82, Folder 962)
    - "Doing Better and Feeling Worse" - Herb Klarman, 1976 (Box 82, Folder 963)
    - "Doing Better and Feeling Worse" - John H. Knowles, 1974-1977 (Box 82, Folder 964)
    - "Doing Better and Feeling Worse" - John H. Knowles, 1974-1977 (Box 82, Folder 965)
    - "Doing Better and Feeling Worse" - John H. Knowles, 1974-1977 (Box 82, Folder 966)
    - "Doing Better and Feeling Worse" - Walsh McDermott, 1976 (Box 82, Folder 967)
    - "Doing Better and Feeling Worse" - Stan Reiser, 1976 (Box 82, Folder 968)
    - "Doing Better and Feeling Worse" - Julius Richmond, 1975-1976 (Box 83, Folder 969)
    - "Doing Better and Feeling Worse" - David E. Rogers, 1975-1976 (Box 83, Folder 970)
    - "Doing Better and Feeling Worse" - Ernest Saward, 1975-1976 (Box 83, Folder 971)
    - "Doing Better and Feeling Worse" - Lewis Thomas, 1975-1976 (Box 83, Folder 972)
    - "Doing Better and Feeling Worse" - Aaron Wildovsky, 1975-1976 (Box 83, Folder 973)
    - "Doing Better and Feeling Worse" - Aaron Wildovsky, 1975-1976 (Box 83, Folder 974)
    - "Doing Better and Feeling Worse" - General Correspondence, August 1974-1977 (Box 83, Folder 975)
    - "Doing Better and Feeling Worse" - General Correspondence, August 1974-1977 (Box 83, Folder 976)
    - "Doing Better and Feeling Worse" - General Correspondence, June-July 1974 (Box 84, Folder 977)
    - "Doing Better and Feeling Worse" - Reviews, 1977 (Box 84, Folder 978)
    - Duke University, 1972-1976, 1978 (Box 84, Folder 979)
    - Duke University, 1972-1976, 1978 (Box 84, Folder 980)
    - Duke University, 1972-1976, 1978 (Box 84, Folder 981)
    - Duke University - Center for International Studies, 1975 (Box 84, Folder 982)
    - General Correspondence, August 1977-January 1979 (Box 84, Folder 983)
    - General Correspondence, June 1972-July 1977 (Box 85, Folder 984)
    - General Correspondence, June 1972-July 1977 (Box 85, Folder 985)
    - General Correspondence, June 1972-July 1977 (Box 85, Folder 986)
    - General Correspondence, June 1972-July 1977 (Box 85, Folder 987)
    - General Correspondence, June 1972-July 1977 (Box 85, Folder 988)
    - General Telephone and Electronics Corporation, 1972-1978 (Box 86, Folder 989)
    - General Telephone and Electronics Corporation, 1972-1978 (Box 86, Folder 990)
    - Hall of Fame, 1972-1976 (Box 86, Folder 991)
    - Harvard, 1972-1978 (Box 87, Folder 992)
    - Harvard, 1972-1978 (Box 87, Folder 993)
    - Harvard, 1972-1978 (Box 87, Folder 994)
    - Harvard, 1972-1978 (Box 87, Folder 995)
    - Harvard, 1972-1978 (Box 87, Folder 996)
    - Harvard, 1972-1978 (Box 87, Folder 997)
    - Harvard - Visiting Committee to the Divinity School, 1973-1976 (Box 88, Folder 998)
    - "Health and Medical Services Review", 1977-1978 (Box 88, Folder 999)
    - Hospital Administrators Correspondence Club, 1973 (Box 88, Folder 1000)
    - Institute International du Stress, 1977-1978 (Box 88, Folder 1001)
    - Institute of Medicine, 1974-1978 (Box 88, Folder 1002)
    - Institute of Medicine - Committee on International Health, 1977 (Box 88, Folder 1003)
    - Institute of Medicine - Committee on International Health, 1977 (Box 88, Folder 1004)
    - Institute of Medicine - Committee on International Health, 1977 (Box 88, Folder 1005)
    - Institute of Medicine - National Academy of Science, 1972-1973 (Box 88, Folder 1006)
    - Institute of Medicine - National Academy of Science - Disease Prevention, 1976-1977 (Box 88, Folder 1007)
    - Internal Revenue Service - Massachusetts General Hospital (MGH), 1973 (Box 89, Folder 1008)
    - Josiah Macy, Jr. Foundation - V. Ramaligaswami, 1976 (Box 89, Folder 1009)
    - Kennedy Oral History Program, 1974 (Box 89, Folder 1010)
    - MacNeil-Lehrer Report, 1978 (Box 89, Folder 1011)
    - Massachusetts General Hospital, 1972-1976 (Box 89, Folder 1012)
    - "Medical World News" Editorial Board, 1974 (Box 89, Folder 1013)
    - Moore McCormack Resources, Inc., 1978 (Box 89, Folder 1014)
    - National Academy of Science, 1975 (Box 89, Folder 1015)
    - National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities, 1972, 1976-1977 (Box 89, Folder 1016)
    - National Institute of Health, 1975 (Box 89, Folder 1017)
    - Nelson, David S., 1968 (Box 89, Folder 1018)
    - New England Conservatory of Music, 1975 (Box 89, Folder 1019)
    - New York Medical College, 1977 (Box 89, Folder 1020)
    - New York Medical Registration, 1971-1978 (Box 89, Folder 1021)
    - New York University, 1972-1979 (Box 89, Folder 1022)
    - Old Docs Club, 1972-1973 (Box 89, Folder 1023)
    - Pat Collins Show, 1976 (Box 89, Folder 1024)
    - "Pharos", 1972-1977 (Box 89, Folder 1025)
    - Pratt Institute, 1973 (Box 89, Folder 1026)
    - Rizgel, Margaret (Box 89, Folder 1027)
    - Royal Society of Medicine, 1971-1975 (Box 89, Folder 1028)
    - Random House (Box 89, Folder 1029)
    - Scientists and Other Citizens, 1978 (Box 89, Folder 1030)
    - Smith College, 1976-1977 (Box 90, Folder 1031)
    - Society of Medical Administrators, 1975, 1977 (Box 90, Folder 1032)
    - Somerset Club, 1973 (Box 90, Folder 1033)
    - "The Struggle to Stay Healthy" - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 90, Folder 1034)
    - Sullivan & Worcester, 1973 (Box 90, Folder 1035)
    - Sweet, William H., 1972 (Box 90, Folder 1036)
    - Technicare, 1972-1979 (Box 90, Folder 1037)
    - United Fund, 1972-1975 (Box 90, Folder 1038)
    - United Hospital Fund of New York, 1972 (Box 90, Folder 1039)
    - United Nations Association of the United States of America, 1972-1975 (Box 90, Folder 1040)
    - United Nations Association of the United States of America, 1972-1975 (Box 90, Folder 1041)
    - United Way, 1978 (Box 90, Folder 1042)
    - University of Pennsylvania, 1972, 1975-1977 (Box 90, Folder 1043)
    - University of Miami, 1977-1978 (Box 90, Folder 1044)
    - Washington University, 1973-1978 (Box 90, Folder 1045)
    - Yale University, 1972-1974 (Box 90, Folder 1046)
    - Alphabetical File (A-Go), 1972-1975 (Box 91, Folder 1047)
    - Alphabetical File (A-Go), 1972-1975 (Box 91, Folder 1048)
    - Alphabetical File (A-Go), 1972-1975 (Box 91, Folder 1049)
    - Alphabetical File (A-Go), 1972-1975 (Box 91, Folder 1050)
    - Alphabetical File (A-Go), 1972-1975 (Box 91, Folder 1051)
    - Alphabetical File (A-Go), 1972-1975 (Box 91, Folder 1052)
    - Alphabetical File (A-Go), 1972-1975 (Box 91, Folder 1053)
    - Alphabetical File (Gr-P), 1972-1975 (Box 92, Folder 1054)
    - Alphabetical File (Gr-P), 1972-1975 (Box 92, Folder 1055)
    - Alphabetical File (Gr-P), 1972-1975 (Box 92, Folder 1056)
    - Alphabetical File (Gr-P), 1972-1975 (Box 92, Folder 1057)
    - Alphabetical File (Gr-P), 1972-1975 (Box 92, Folder 1058)
    - Alphabetical File (Gr-P), 1972-1975 (Box 92, Folder 1059)
    - Alphabetical File (R-Z), 1972-1975 (Box 93, Folder 1060)
    - Alphabetical File (R-Z), 1972-1975 (Box 93, Folder 1061)
    - Alphabetical File (R-Z), 1972-1975 (Box 93, Folder 1062)
    - Alphabetical File (R-Z), 1972-1975 (Box 93, Folder 1063)
  - The Rockefeller Foundation - Personal, C
    Subseries C contains biographical material and correspondence relating to Dr. Knowles's personal interests, including clubs and finances. It also includes get-well correspondence to Dr. Knowles during his illness and sympathy letters to Mrs. Knowles after his death.
    - Biographical Material (Box 93, Folder 1064)
    - Contributions, 1972-1978 (Box 93, Folder 1065)
    - General Correspondence, 1972-1979 (Box 94, Folder 1066)
    - General Correspondence, 1972-1979 (Box 94, Folder 1067)
    - General Correspondence, 1972-1979 (Box 94, Folder 1068)
    - General Correspondence, 1972-1979 (Box 94, Folder 1069)
    - General Correspondence, 1972-1979 (Box 94, Folder 1070)
    - General Correspondence (Box 94, Folder 1071)
      Undated, probably 1975-1976.
    - Investors Bank & Trust Company (Box 94, Folder 1072)
    - Irwin Trust Company, 1977 (Box 94, Folder 1073)
    - Museum of Science, 1976 (Box 95, Folder 1074)
    - Myopia Hunt Club, 1973 (Box 95, Folder 1075)
    - New England Patriots, 1972-1974 (Box 95, Folder 1076)
    - Pops Concert Ball, 1976 (Box 95, Folder 1077)
    - Racquet & Tennis Club, 1975, 1978 (Box 95, Folder 1078)
    - River Club, 1973 (Box 95, Folder 1079)
    - Get-Well Correspondence - Alphabetical List, 1979 (Box 95, Folder 1080)
    - Get-Well Correspondence - Alphabetical List, 1979 (Box 95, Folder 1081)
    - Get-Well Correspondence - Rockefeller Foundation Staff List, 1979 (Box 95, Folder 1082)
    - Get-Well Correspondence - Rockefeller Foundation Trustees List, 1979 (Box 95, Folder 1083)
    - Get-Well Correspondence - Foundation Heads List, 1979 (Box 95, Folder 1084)
    - Get-Well Correspondence - Heads of Boards List, 1979 (Box 95, Folder 1085)
    - Get-Well Correspondence - Other Lists, 1979 (Box 95, Folder 1086)
    - Get-Well Correspondence - General, 1979 (Box 95, Folder 1087)
    - Get-Well Cards, 1979 (Box 95, Folder 1088)
    - Get-Well Cards, 1979 (Box 95, Folder 1089)
    - Get-Well Cards, 1979 (Box 96, Folder 1090)
    - Get-Well Correspondence - to Edith Knowles, 1979 (Box 96, Folder 1091)
    - Sympathy Letters, March 8-November 25, 1979 (Box 96, Folder 1092)
    - Sympathy Letters, March 8-November 25, 1979 (Box 96, Folder 1093)
    - Sympathy Letters, March 8-November 25, 1979 (Box 96, Folder 1094)
    - Sympathy Letters, March 8-November 25, 1979 (Box 96, Folder 1095)
    - Sympathy Letters, March 6-8, 1979 (Box 97, Folder 1096)
    - Sympathy Letters, March 1979 (Box 97, Folder 1097)
    - Sympathy Letters, undated (Box 97, Folder 1098)
    - Sympathy Letters - to The Rockefeller Foundation, March-December 1979 (Box 97, Folder 1099)
    - Sympathy Letters - Third Party, March-April 1979 (Box 97, Folder 1100)
    - Sympathy Letters - from Rockefeller Foundation Staff, March 1979 (Box 97, Folder 1101)
    - Sympathy Telegrams, March 1979 (Box 97, Folder 1102)
    - Sympathy Telegrams - Third Party, March 1979 (Box 97, Folder 1103)
    - Memorials, 1979 (Box 97, Folder 1104)
  - The Rockefeller Foundation - Manuscripts, D
    Subseries D consists of manuscripts of articles, books, and speeches. Included is the incomplete manuscript "Essays on Medicine and Health."
    - List of Publications, 1969-1978 (Box 97, Folder 1105)
    - Allentown and Sacred Heart Hospital Center, 1973 (Box 97, Folder 1106)
    - "American Doctor" (Box 97, Folder 1107)
    - "American Medicine and World Health", 1976 (Box 98, Folder 1108)
    - American Public Health Association - 100th Annual Convention, 1972 (Box 98, Folder 1109)
    - Belmont Hill School Commencement, 1973 (Box 98, Folder 1110)
    - Centro Internacional de Agricultura Tropical (CIAT) Dedication, 1973 (Box 98, Folder 1111)
    - "Clarity of Thought and Higher Education", 1975-1976 (Box 98, Folder 1112)
    - "Coming Change in Medicine", 1974 (Box 98, Folder 1113)
    - "Conflect and Interdependence", 1973 (Box 98, Folder 1114)
    - "Department of Medicine", 1974 (Box 98, Folder 1115)
    - "Doing Better and Feeling Worse: Perspectives in American Health", 1977-1979 (Box 98, Folder 1116)
    - "Elements of a Domestic Health Policy", 1975 (Box 98, Folder 1117)
    - "Essays on Medicine and Health" - Chapters 1-21 (Box 98, Folder 1118)
    - "Essays on Medicine and Health" - Chapters 1-21 (Box 98, Folder 1119)
    - "Essays on Medicine and Health" - Chapters 1-21 (Box 98, Folder 1120)
    - "Essays on Medicine and Health" - Chapters 22-27 (Box 99, Folder 1121)
    - "Essays on Medicine and Health" - Chapters 22-27 (Box 99, Folder 1122)
    - "Federal Expenditures, Welfare, Income Distribution" (Box 99, Folder 1123)
    - "Food, Energy and American Austerity", 1974 (Box 99, Folder 1124)
    - Forward to "The Health Handbook", 1979 (Box 99, Folder 1125)
    - "Functions of a University", 1976 (Box 99, Folder 1126)
    - "Future Directions in Health Care: The Dimensions of Medicine - Introduction", 1975 (Box 99, Folder 1127)
    - "Future of Academic Community Medicine in Developing Countries", 1978 (Box 99, Folder 1128)
    - "Future of Foundations", 1972 (Box 99, Folder 1129)
    - "Global Food Problems and the Chinese Model", 1975 (Box 99, Folder 1130)
    - Grantmakers on Health Care Delivery Talk, 1974 (Box 99, Folder 1131)
    - Harvard College Fund Assembly Dinner Talk, 1972 (Box 99, Folder 1132)
    - "Health and Economic Security", 1974 (Box 99, Folder 1133)
    - "Health and Technology", 1978 (Box 99, Folder 1134)
    - "Health and the Quality of Life", 1974 (Box 99, Folder 1135)
    - "Health in America", 1973 (Box 99, Folder 1136)
    - "Health in the United States", 1976 (Box 99, Folder 1137)
    - "Health, Population and Development", 1980 (Box 99, Folder 1138)
    - "Health System and the Supreme Court Decision: An Affirmative Response", 1973 (Box 99, Folder 1139)
    - Hesburgh Dinner Talk, 1977 (Box 99, Folder 1140)
    - "Hospitals in the United States", 1973 (Box 99, Folder 1141)
    - "Hunger, Politics and Markets", 1975 (Box 99, Folder 1142)
    - "Implementing the Abortion Decision", 1973 (Box 100, Folder 1143)
    - "Increasing Emphasis on Preventative Medicine", 1976-1977 (Box 100, Folder 1144)
    - "Individualism, Social Welfare and the Frontier in American Life" (Box 100, Folder 1145)
    - "Interdependence and the Global Crisis", 1974 (Box 100, Folder 1146)
    - "Is More Better", 1975 (Box 100, Folder 1147)
    - "Is There a Doctor Shortage", 1972 (Box 100, Folder 1148)
    - Japanese Philanthropy Project Talk, 1974 (Box 100, Folder 1149)
    - Letters to the Editor, 1976-1977 (Box 100, Folder 1150)
    - "Looking a Gift Horse in the Mouth", 1975 (Box 100, Folder 1151)
    - "Means to the Ends of The Rockefeller Foundation", 1974 (Box 100, Folder 1152)
    - "Medicine Tomorrow - More Groups, More Outpatient Services, More Prevention", 1977 (Box 100, Folder 1153)
    - "Meeting the World's Food Needs", 1974 (Box 100, Folder 1154)